Our little Hotaru's really gone
and become someone's girlfriend now.
Congratulations again, Hotaru.
I'm so happy for you!
The only reason someone like me
was able to fall in love
is because I got so much good
advice from the two of you.
Thank you so much.
So, what are you two going to do during
spring break? Go on a bunch of dates?
Hmm...
But we see each other all the time at work.
Huh?
Hananoi-kun got a job
at the place where I work.
Huh?!
Hotaru-chan, I want to ask you something.
Um...
If it's okay with you, Hotaru-chan,
I want to spend more time together.
I-I wasn't so sure about it either, but he
promised to keep it professional at work.
Well, as long as you're okay with it.
Still, you should try
to maintain a little distance.
I mean, can someone like him
who has zero interest in strangers
even work a customer service job?
Episode 8
My First Pet
Zero interest in strangers, huh?
I guess I kind of knew that...
But it hasn't caused problems so far,
and everyone here's real nice.
Everything should be fine, right?
Um, Hananoi-kun!
Can I please take your picture?!
No way.
E-Everyone really is nice...
Oh, Hotaru-chan! Good morning.
G-Good morning.
Gosh, I'm still not used to this!
That covers it for now.
Okay, let's make this another great day.
We'll do our best!
Oh, Hananoi, come with me.
And that's how it's done. You get all that?
Yes.
The register should be your priority,
so just come out on the floor when you can.
You won't get to this all.
All right.
I heard that you're Hinase-san's
boyfriend. Is that right?
Yes, that's correct.
Well, try not to show it
when you're on the job, okay?
You two are here to work, after all.
I give thanks to this lovely
world and to Hota-chan!
I still can't believe you two
get to work together.
I'm so jealous! I never had anything
like that when I was younger.
Even Yao-kun is super popular.
Please stop talking like I get all the girls.
I haven't had much luck
when it comes to romance.
Still, I have more respect for people
who take good care of their friends,
even if they've never been in love.
The manager asked if you could bundle
these magazines together.
Roger that.
H-Hananoi-kun?
O-Oh, that's right.
I was worried about things
between him and Yao-kun...
But all seems well now, I suppose.
Oh.
Good work today.
Guess he's dropped the act now.
Hey, I know I made a bad
impression when we met,
but Hotako and I are just friends.
Since we're working together now,
let's try to get along, okay?
Would you knock it off
with the "Hotako" stuff?
I don't know about your past, but you don't look
like you're even much "friends" anymore to me.
Stay away from Hotaru-chan, okay?
Yeesh, I don't think he likes me.
Hananoi-kun! Thanks for waiting.
Good job today, Hotaru-chan.
How are you getting along with Manager Kuroe?
Hmm...
As long as I'm with you, it's all good.
That must mean there's been some friction.
Manager Kuroe can be pretty strict.
Maybe I can help smooth things over.
I'll have to keep an eye on things.
By the way, Hananoi-kun, do you want
to go to a cafe or something?
And so, now that we're officially dating,
let's discuss our policies going forward!
Policies?
Like we discussed the other day, we each
have what's important to us in a relationship.
So if you don't mind, can you maybe tell me
things you wouldn't want me to do?
I may not be able to honor everything,
but just like there are things we want to do,
it's important to be on the same page
about what we don't want.
This is kind of sudden...
What about you?
Me?
I, well...
Um...
I dunno...
Let me think. Things I don't want you to do...
I don't want you to leave
me behind, I guess.
Huh?
Yeah. I don't want you to leave me behind.
We are now closed for the day.
I can finally get started
on restocking the shelves.
Hmm?
It's already done.
Good evening—
Oh!
Wh-What's all this?
Well, we got a huge order of dictionaries
for new elementary school students.
They have to be delivered soon, so I guess
I'll stay late after closing to wrap them all.
We'd like to help!
We can do them bit by bit
during business hours.
Thanks. That'd be a huge help.
Then it's settled!
You guys can show off the
wrapping skills you've practiced!
Yeah!
We are now closed for the day.
You're kidding me. You did all
this with just the three of you?
We're experts at a quick,
clean wrapping job now.
Plus, it was the four of us!
Hananoi-kun helped too!
Huh...
But Hananoi just started here.
He hasn't learned how to wrap yet.
He said he watched other people
doing it and practiced at home.
U-Um, Hananoi-kun is always like that!
I guess you could say he's a good student.
Good work again today.
You can call it a night.
All right.
You sure are something.
You're just a part-timer.
Why are you putting in so much effort?
I don't care what you think of me,
but I don't want to make Hinase-san look bad.
What does that mean?
I don't think you like me very much, Manager.
Huh? Why would you say—
Oh.
You two are here to work, after all.
Ah...
Okay, sorry. That was my bad.
I was out of line.
It's not like... I mean...
Supervising a regular customer
is just awkward for me.
I wasn't sure how to treat you, I guess.
You used to shop here all the time, right?
You always bought the books I made
displays for, so I remember you.
Boy, I sure am exhausted today!
But Manager Kuroe gave me cocoa as thanks.
He gave me a coffee.
I got it in my head that he was kind of
scary, but he's actually nice.
Yeah.
Oh... Are you still having trouble
getting along with him?
No, well...
Just that Kuroe-san remembers that I've been
frequenting the store since a long time ago.
It's kind of... embarrassing.
He... He's blushing?! Hananoi-kun's blushing!
I'm glad I said I didn't mind
working together.
Regardless of the reason,
it can't be a bad thing for Hananoi-kun
to open himself up to new things, right?
Is something wrong?
Nope!
Oh, the bus is here.
Okay, Hananoi-kun. See you tomorrow!
I want to stay with you...
just a little longer.
I'm glad that I get to spend
more time with you,
but I can't really touch
you unless we're alone.
I-I guess you're right.
H-Hananoi-kun?
I figure if we do this more,
you'll get used to it.
What? I don't know if
I'll ever get used to this!
It feels like ever since
you told me you liked me,
I've been walking on air.
Me too. I've been walking
on air this whole time.
One day,
when we finally share a real kiss,
I want you to be as elated as I will be.
So when your heart is ready for it
and you decide you want it,
give me a signal, okay?
I can't even imagine it yet,
but if we both keep doing things
at our own pace... that works, right?
Huh? Keigo-kun invited you
over to his house, Kyo-chan?
Yeah. This is actually the first time.
But listen, Kei-chan says...
that his family has an absolutely
giant golden retriever!
Whoa!
And so that's why I wanted to ask you,
Yao-kun. Since you have a dog,
you must know a few tricks
for befriending them.
Tricks, huh?
Oh.
Well, why don't you just come over?
Where'd that come from?
I mean, won't it help to actually
spend time with a dog?
You can come too, Hananoi.
Do you mind if I check with my friend first?
Kyo-chan, we haven't made it to the dog yet.
Just leave me here and go on without me!
Okay, but please make sure you come.
Mm-hmm.
Sorry to drag you along.
Are you okay with this?
I mean, with Yao-kun and all.
It'll be fine.
But are you okay with this, Hotaru-chan?
I thought that you were avoiding Yao-kun.
Huh? Why?
Was I acting strange or something?
I wasn't trying to avoid him.
Um, Yao-kun and I go way back,
so things are a little awkward.
But today's a special opportunity.
If it's to help Kyo-chan,
I'll do whatever I can.
Thanks for having us... over!
We're coming in.
Oh! Is that Hotaru?
I dunno. Maybe it's just the name,
but doesn't she kinda look like you?
Huh?
I know what you mean.
They have the exact same eyebrows.
Yao-kun, weren't you Hotaru's classmate
in elementary school?
Yup. Class 1 in sixth grade.
I met her in the second year of junior high.
I bet in middle school, Hota—
Um, what was Hinase like then?
Hmm, she was basically the same.
Huh? What did he just call me?
She was a little quieter back then.
Like she kept her guard up, I guess?
Huh?
Yeah, I was real shocked when I heard
you used to have guy friends like Yao-kun!
K-Kyo-chan, that's ancient history.
She was quiet in elementary school too.
But y'know, Hinase was so pure. If anyone
was in trouble, she'd always try to help.
You were such a sweetheart.
So she's always been like that, huh?
Yeah, no, I'm nothing that special.
Hey, I know. I've still got our yearbook—
Didn't we come to play with the dog?
You're right. Sorry, sorry.
Hotaru, these people are my friends.
C-Come here, Hotaru!
Don't startle her. Just try to be gentle.
Kyo-chan! I'll try going first.
Up we go.
Kyo-chan!
See? It's okay!
It's Hotaru, it's Hotaru,
it's Hotaru, it's Hotaru!
You mean me?
Th-This might actually be okay.
Right?
Hananoi, why don't you
come pet Hotaru too?
I'm good.
C'mon, don't be like that.
There, there.
You're a good girl, Hotaru.
I feel like I'm watching
something I shouldn't be.
Hey, I think I'm getting used to this.
Really? I'm so glad.
We can thank Yao-kun for that.
Yup.
You too, Hotaru. Thanks.
All this for a friend, huh?
Hinase really is a good person.
"Hinase"?
Huh?
You're the one who told me
not to call her Hotako.
I mean, she's asked me that before, too.
She's so nice, but she hates me.
I wonder what I did wrong.
She say anything to you?
I don't know anything.
Oh, okay.
Say, you know what? I feel like I've heard
the name Hananoi somewhere before.
Have we meet before or something?
Who knows?
It looked like Kyo-chan was able
to get over her fear a little. I'm so glad.
You do seem happy.
Yeah!
Kyo-chan was thrilled, so I am too.
I've got to find a way to thank Yao-kun.
I'm a little jealous.
Huh?
You really went out of your way for Asami-san.
She must be over the moon.
I-It was no big deal.
You don't think so? Most people wouldn't
go so far to help a friend.
I mean, honestly, she's always been
the one helping me out.
Didn't Kyo-chan mention it?
I was pretty gloomy in middle school.
After what happened in elementary school,
I was too scared to make friends.
I tried to keep to myself.
That's when I met Kyo-chan.
I was actually a little scared to hang out
with someone who was so open about love.
But for whatever reason,
I had so much fun when I was with her.
After a while, even though I
still didn't understand it,
the idea of falling head over heels in love
started to sound so nice.
If it weren't for Kyo-chan, I might never
have wanted to try falling in love myself.
I'm never much help when we have girl talk,
so I'm really glad I was
able to help her today!
Thank you for everything
today too, Hananoi-kun.
Right...
So it was Asami-san who was there
for Hotaru-chan when she was at her lowest.
I can't really compete with that.
Anyway, Hotaru sure was a cutey.
Oh! I-I mean the dog!
Everyone was all "Hotaru this, Hotaru that"
today. It started to feel weird.
Like when you...
Er, forget I said that!
There, there. To me, you'll always be
the best girl, Hotaru-chan.
Th-That's not what I meant!
Now you're blushing!
Year 6, Class 1
Hinase Hotaru
It's been ages since I saw
her smile like she used to.
Otowa Municipal South Elementary School, Otowa City
Graduation Album
Wait, is that...
I can't stand it.
Back then, why did I...?
Year 6, Class 5